<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-15T12:52:48-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">lonoak</title><subtitle>Lonoak is a blog founded by Reed Barber where you can find excellent tips on whatever I think is relevant, not to mention a lot of creative ideas &amp; usefull tech tips. If you are a creative tech professional who wants to learn the nuts and bolts of anything, maybe this blog is for you. Maybe.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Using server alerts to generate Todoist tasks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/update/todoist/2018/08/15/server-alerts-todoist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using server alerts to generate Todoist tasks" /><published>2018-08-15T11:00:02-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-15T11:00:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/update/todoist/2018/08/15/server-alerts-todoist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/update/todoist/2018/08/15/server-alerts-todoist.html">&lt;p&gt;I manage a few different servers for several different friends and clients. As part of managing each server and site hosted on it, I’ll typically receive alerts for errors, common tasks or downtime. For a while I had settled on filing these alerts into a separate mailbox to keep them from overwhelming my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works for a while, but I’d occasionally miss an important alert or message from one of the servers. In an effort to manage my responsibilities I had started using Todoist to track my responsibilities. I set up an alias pointing to my email to inbox Todoist address, tuned the server alerts for volume and importance and routed them to this new alias. Now, if I get an actionable alert for, say, server downtime, it’s routed to my inbox with all the relevant details to resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I manage a few different servers for several different friends and clients. As part of managing each server and site hosted on it, I’ll typically receive alerts for errors, common tasks or downtime. For a while I had settled on filing these alerts into a separate mailbox to keep them from overwhelming my inbox. This works for a while, but I’d occasionally miss an important alert or message from one of the servers. In an effort to manage my responsibilities I had started using Todoist to track my responsibilities. I set up an alias pointing to my email to inbox Todoist address, tuned the server alerts for volume and importance and routed them to this new alias. Now, if I get an actionable alert for, say, server downtime, it’s routed to my inbox with all the relevant details to resolve the issue.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Updating to the latest version of git on Ubuntu</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/update/ubuntu/git/2018/08/15/update-git-ubuntu.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Updating to the latest version of git on Ubuntu" /><published>2018-08-15T10:00:02-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-15T10:00:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/update/ubuntu/git/2018/08/15/update-git-ubuntu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/update/ubuntu/git/2018/08/15/update-git-ubuntu.html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re using git on Ubuntu, the version distributed via apt may not be the newest version of git (I use git to deploy changes on all of the sites I manage). You can install the latest stable version of git provided by the maintainers as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt; sudo add-apt-repository ppa:git-core/ppa &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt; sudo apt-get update &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you’re using git on Ubuntu, the version distributed via apt may not be the newest version of git (I use git to deploy changes on all of the sites I manage). You can install the latest stable version of git provided by the maintainers as follows: sudo add-apt-repository ppa:git-core/ppa sudo apt-get update</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We Should All Care About Encryption</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/update/encryption/2018/08/15/care-obout-encryption.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Should All Care About Encryption" /><published>2018-08-15T05:00:02-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-15T05:00:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/update/encryption/2018/08/15/care-obout-encryption</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/update/encryption/2018/08/15/care-obout-encryption.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.ted.com/why-we-should-all-care-about-encryption-really/&quot;&gt;Andy Yen, via TED.com:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we squander privacy by allowing back doors or building illicit vulnerabilities into encryption tools, there is nothing to protect us from prying corporations, spying governments or even criminals bent on abusing our data. Unfortunately, there is no such thing as a back door that only lets the good guys in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Data must always be encrypted, end-to-end, period — before it leaves your computer. Privacy is a fundamental right. Let’s not squander it in the name of security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Andy Yen, via TED.com: If we squander privacy by allowing back doors or building illicit vulnerabilities into encryption tools, there is nothing to protect us from prying corporations, spying governments or even criminals bent on abusing our data. Unfortunately, there is no such thing as a back door that only lets the good guys in. Data must always be encrypted, end-to-end, period — before it leaves your computer. Privacy is a fundamental right. Let’s not squander it in the name of security.</summary></entry></feed>